<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Luciana Etcheverry</title>
    <link>lucianaetcheverry.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Luciana Etcheverry</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="lucianaetcheverry.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>lucianaetcheverry.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>lucianaetcheverry.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Working papers  Work half-time, receive full-time pay: Effect of novel family policy on female labor market outcomes (Job Market Paper)
Many countries provide paid family leave to increase female labor force participation, improve gender equality, and foster family wellbeing. Yet, a large percentage of women do not return to work after maternity leave. Can a subsidy that allows a more flexible re-introduction to work increase work attachment after birth? I leverage the implementation of a subsidy in Uruguay that allows parents to work half-time while receiving full-time pay for 4 month after the culmination of maternity leave to answer this question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>lucianaetcheverry.com/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>lucianaetcheverry.com/teaching/</guid>
      <description>At University of Oregon as the instructor of record I have taught advanced econometrics, labor, and development economics, managed teaching assistants and TA&amp;rsquo;ed for a variety of courses. I have been distinguished with a Graduate Teaching Award and received excellent student feedback. Below you can find course summaries, materials, and student feedback.
Independent Instructor EC 350: Issues in Labor Economics (Spring 2019, Spring 2020)
Syllabus
In this course, students explore issues in the labor market using insights from economic theory and empirical papers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>